RYAN WELLMAN

50 St Pancras Gardens, Lewes, BN7 1HZ

07921020114

Rwellman.dev@gmail.com

I have a strong passion for Frontend development, specializing in JavaScript, React, CSS and HTML. Self-development and learning are two qualities I pride myself on. With the aid of online boot camp 'Scrimba', I have managed to successfully take the leap from Guitar Tutor to Frontend developer. I take a great deal of enjoyment in learning new languages and implementing newly found knowledge to solve problems creatively. Working as a music tutor has taught me that problems often have multiple different solutions. I am currently invested in refining my JavaScript knowledge and picking up basic PHP and SOL.

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2017 - PRESENT

GUITAR TUTOR, SELF EMPLOYED

- Achieved a pass rate of 95% in exams, with 88% of students passing with a Merit or higher.
- Building & maintaining positive relationships with both students and parents.
- Maintain up to date books for yearly tax return.
- Invoice and chase payments from clients using 'My Music Staff' software.
- Providing quality lesson plans on a weekly basis.
- Adapted to weekly online lessons during the pandemic in 2020-2021.

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

VISITING GUITAR TUTOR, WEST SUSSEX MUSIC

- Evaluating class progress and adjusting strategies to maintain progress and learning.
- Maintaining good communication with parents through email and telephone requests for assistance with specific questions and updates on pupil progress.
- Providing a safe and enjoyable learning atmosphere whilst following safeguarding guidelines.
- Efficient time management to ensure punctuality and professionalism with varied schedule
- Updating required logs and student documentation

EDUCATION

MAY 2017

BA(HONS) MUSIC, UNIVERSITY OF CHICHESTER

1:1

CURRENT

FRONTEND DEVELOPER CAREER PATH, SCRIMBA

Currently working towards finishing the frontend developer career path with Scrimba. Learning HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and GitHub.

SKILLS

- HTML5 & CSS3
- JavaScript / ES6
- React
- Git

- Client assessment and analysis
- Critical Thinking
- Attention to detail
- Highly organized
- Self-learning

ACHIEVEMENTS

Perform as lead guitarist of Indie rock band 'Luna Blue'. Recently we have achieved the following;

- Performed multiple main stages at festivals in the UK, including 'El Dorado' and 'Amprocks'.
- Music has been Featured on BBC radio 1.
- BBC introducing Sussex 'Track of the Day' multiple times.
- Obtained over 600,000 total streams on Spotify.
- Worked with producer of renown band 'Fickle Friends'.